Guide to the Ezra Pound Papers Addition
Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library
- Correspondence, 1906-72; Series I; 11.25; (28 boxes)
  - Monotti, Francesco, 1944 Mar 31 (Box 12, Folder 293)
  - Monroe, Harriet, 1929 Dec 17 (Box 12, Folder 294)
  - Montanari, Filippo, 1962-67, n.d. (Box 12, Folder 295)
  - Moore, Frank L., 1965-72 (Box 12, Folder 296)
  - Moore, Harry T., 1965 Dec 9 (Box 12, Folder 297)
  - Moore, Marianne, 1934-67 (Box 12, Folder 298-99)
    See also: Chester Page, Box 13, folder 333
  - Morgan, Frederick
    See: The Hudson Review, Box 8, folder 191
  - Mumford, Lewis
    See: American Caravan
  - Murphy, William A., 1966-70, n.d. (Box 12, Folder 300)
  - Museé National d'Art Moderne, 1965-68 (Box 12, Folder 301)
  - "N" general, 1928-72, n.d. (Box 12, Folder 302-06)
  - National Broadcasting Company, 1966 Jul 18 (Box 12, Folder 307)
  - Neame, Alan, 1962, 1971 (Box 12, Folder 308)
  - New Directions, 1962-70 (Box 12, Folder 309)
    See also: James Laughlin, Box 10, folder 226
  - The New Republic, 1930 May 10 (Box 12, Folder 310)
  - New York Herald, n.d. (Box 12, Folder 311)
  - New York Times, 1965 Aug 6 (Box 12, Folder 312)
  - Niehans, Paul, 1971, n.d. (Box 12, Folder 313)
  - Norman, Charles, 1960 Sep 19 (Box 12, Folder 314)
  - "O" general, 1961-72 (Box 13, Folder 315-16)
  - Odlin, Reno, 1962-63 (Box 13, Folder 317)
  - O'Grady, Desmond, 1966-71 (Box 13, Folder 318-20)
  - Olson (?), Charles, n.d. (Box 13, Folder 321)
  - Oppen, George, 1963 (Box 13, Folder 322)
  - Oshima, Shotaro, 1964-70 (Box 13, Folder 323)
  - Overholser, Winfred, 1963 Jul 2 (Box 13, Folder 324)
  - "P" General, [1927]-1980 (Box 13, Folder 325-32)
  - Page, Chester, 1969, 1971 (Box 13, Folder 333)
  - Paideuma, 1971-72 (Box 13, Folder 334)
  - Paige, Douglas D., 1947-72 (Box 13, Folder 335)
  - Paigin (?), 1947-48 (Box 13, Folder 336)
  - Parens, Rachel Anto, 1965 (Box 13, Folder 337)
  - The Paris Review, 1965 Mar 1 (Box 13, Folder 338)
  - Partito Fascista Repubblicano, 1943-44 (Box 13, Folder 339)
  - Patmore, Brigit, 1961-65 (Box 13, Folder 340-41)
  - Pea, Enrico, n.d. (Box 14, Folder 342)
  - Pearlman, Daniel, 1968-69 (Box 14, Folder 343)
  - Pearn, Pollinger, and Higham, Ltd.
    See Lawrence Pollinger
  - Pearson, Norman Holmes, 1961-70 (Box 14, Folder 344)
  - Pensione La Calcina, 1964 Jul 15 (Box 14, Folder 345)
  - Pescetto, Alberto (?), 1969 (Box 14, Folder 346)
  - Poetry, 1962, 1972 (Box 14, Folder 347)
  - Poetry Book Society, 1968 Nov 20 (Box 14, Folder 348)
  - The Poetry Society, 1968 Sep 5 (Box 14, Folder 349)
  - Polignac, Wineretta de, [1933], n.d. (Box 14, Folder 350)
  - Pollinger, Lawrence, 1938 (Box 14, Folder 351)
  - Ponder-Greene, Drew, 1966-69 (Box 14, Folder 352)
  - Pound, Dorothy, 1968, n.d. (Box 14, Folder 353)
  - Pound, Homer, 1906(?)-34, n.d. (Box 14, Folder 354-55)
  - Pound, Isabel, 1906-47 (Box 14, Folder 356)
  - Pound, Omar, 1949, 1971 (Box 14, Folder 356)
  - Prospettive, 1939 Sep 9 (Box 14, Folder 357)
  - "Q" General, 1933-72 (Box 14, Folder 358)
  - Quinn, Bernetta, Sister, 1965-72, n.d. (Box 14, Folder 359-61)
  - "R" General, 1930-72 (Box 14, Folder 362-68)
  - Radiotelevisione Italiana (RAI), 1966-70 (Box 15, Folder 369)
  - Rachewiltz, Boris de, 1951-71, n.d. (Box 15, Folder 370)
  - Rachewiltz, Igor de (Box 15, Folder 370)
  - Rachewiltz, Patrizia de
    See: Patrizia De Vroom, Box 23, folder 520
  - Rachewiltz, Walter de, 1952-71 (Box 15, Folder 371-73)
  - Rainer, Dachine, 1969 (Box 15, Folder 374)
  - Read, Forrest, 1964-69 (Box 15, Folder 375)
  - Reck, Michael, 1965-70, n.d. (Box 15, Folder 376)
  - Recontre Mondiale de Poésie, 1967 (Box 15, Folder 377)
  - Red Clay, 1965-70 (Box 15, Folder 378)
  - Reid, Ben, 1963-64 (Box 15, Folder 379)
  - Reznowski, Lorne, 1965-66 (Box 15, Folder 380)
  - Ringer, Gordon, 1950 Jan 22 (Box 15, Folder 381)
  - Ritter, [Fernando?], 1969-70 (Box 15, Folder 382)
  - Robinson, Lennox, 1930 Sep 9 (Box 15, Folder 383)
  - Ronsisvalle, Vanni, n.d. (Box 15, Folder 384)
  - Rossetti, Orio, 1971 (Box 15, Folder 385)
  - Roux, Dominique de, 1962-69, n.d. (Box 15, Folder 386)
  - Rudge, Peter Rudge, Edgar Rudge, Theodore, 1939-67 (Box 15, Folder 387)
  - Russell, Peter (with poems), 1948-72 (Box 15, Folder 388-90)
  - "S" general, 1926-72 (Box 16, Folder 391-405)
  - Saffro, Yale L. (with sketch of Ezra Pound), 1970 (Box 17, Folder 406)
  - St. James Press, 1969-72 (Box 17, Folder 407)
  - Santayana, George, 1946 Jul 19 (Box 17, Folder 408)
  - Scarfoglio, Carlo, 1943, 1952 (Box 17, Folder 409)
  - Schafer, R. Murray, 1969 Jan 16 (Box 17, Folder 410)
  - Scheiwiller, Giovanni, 1931-65 (Box 17, Folder 411-12)
  - Scheiwiller, Giovanni (Vanni), 1962-72, n.d. (Box 17, Folder 413-18)
  - Seel, Else, 1948-71 (Box 17, Folder 419)
  - Sefaris, Giorgio (telegram from Pound) (Box 17, Folder 420)
  - Segger, Frank, 1964-68 (Box 17, Folder 421)
  - Serly, Tibor, 1931-68 (Box 17, Folder 422)
  - Sewanee Review, 1965 (Box 17, Folder 423)
  - Seymour, Alan, 1940 (Box 17, Folder 424)
  - Singh, George, 1966-71 (Box 17, Folder 425)
  - Sitwell, Sacheverell, 1965 Apr 27 (Box 17, Folder 426)
  - Slavin, George, 1946-63 (Box 17, Folder 427-30)
  - Slavin, George, 1964-66 (Box 18, Folder 431-44)
  - Slavin, George, 1967-69, n.d. (Box 19, Folder 445-56)
  - Slavin, George, n.d. (Box 20, Folder 457-69)
  - Slavin, George, n.d. (Box 21, Folder 470-74)
  - Slocum, John (with notes by Pound), 1948 (Box 22, Folder 475)
  - Socci, Robert D., 1971 (Box 22, Folder 476)
  - Socialist America, 1969 (Box 22, Folder 477)
  - Società Ippica Meranese, 1969-71 (Box 22, Folder 478)
  - Somers, Homer, 1965 (Box 22, Folder 479)
  - The Something Else Press, 1964-66 (Box 22, Folder 480)
  - Spann, Marcella, 1961-72 (Box 22, Folder 481-82)
  - Spedick, Charles Elmer, 1965 Feb 2 (Box 22, Folder 483)
  - Spender, Stephen, 1965, n.d. (Box 22, Folder 484)
  - Sperandeo, Giussepina Cosco, [1942]-71 (Box 22, Folder 485)
  - Spira, Robert, 1965-66 (Box 22, Folder 486)
  - Spoleto Festival, 1966-72 (Box 22, Folder 487)
  - Stafford, Jack, 1962-69 (Box 22, Folder 488)
  - Stasiack, Adrian (with sketch of Pound), 1971 (Box 22, Folder 489)
  - State University of New York, 1968, 1972 (Box 22, Folder 490)
  - Stern, Richard, 1963-66, n.d. (Box 22, Folder 491)
  - Stetson, Catherine, 1968-71 (Box 22, Folder 492)
  - Stevens, C. F. Terrell, 1971 Nov 26 (Box 22, Folder 493)
  - Stocchi, Gabriele, 1961-71 (Box 22, Folder 494-95)
  - Stock, Noel, 1962-70 (Box 22, Folder 496)
  - Stokes, Adrian, 1929-72 (Box 22, Folder 497)
  - Straus, Roger, 1965, n.d. (Box 22, Folder 498)
  - Sullivan, J. P., 1964 (Box 22, Folder 499)
  - Swabey, Henry, 1938-71 (Box 22, Folder 500)
  - Szczepanski, Kathryn, 1967-71 (Box 22, Folder 501)
  - "T" general, 1929-72, n.d. (Box 22, Folder 502-05)
  - Tate, Allen, 1965 (Box 22, Folder 506)
  - Territet, Horst Tappe (sketch), 1970 (Box 22, Folder 507)
  - This Is My Best, 1968, n.d. (Box 22, Folder 508)
  - Three Mountains Press (William Bird), 1924 Oct 20 (Box 22, Folder 509)
  - Time Magazine, 1965-67 (Box 22, Folder 510)
  - Tortora, Vincent
    See: Spoleto Festival, Box 22, folder 487
  - "U" general, 1921-72 (Box 23, Folder 511)
  - United States Government (Foreign Service; Congress; Treasury Department), 1940 (Box 23, Folder 512)
  - "V" general, 1962-72 (Box 23, Folder 513-15)
  - Vaio, Giorgio Vaio, Heidi, 1965-66 (Box 23, Folder 516)
  - Vanderpohl (?), 1930 Apr 24 (Box 23, Folder 517)
  - Villa-Lobos, Heitor, n.d. (Box 23, Folder 518)
  - Von Leers, Professor, 1960 Feb 17 (Box 23, Folder 519)
  - Vroom, Patrizia de Rachewiltz de, 1962-71, n.d. (Box 23, Folder 520-21)
  - "W" general, 1930-72, n.d. (Box 23, Folder 522-27)
  - Wadsworth, P. Beaumont, 1966 Oct 20 (Box 24, Folder 528)
  - Wallace, Naomi, 1971 Nov 26 (Box 24, Folder 529)
  - Walter, Susan, 1968 (Box 24, Folder 530)
  - Watkins, Vernon, 1965 Feb 4 (Box 24, Folder 531)
  - Weinberg, Simon (with copies of letters from T. S. Eliot), 1962 Dec 9 (Box 24, Folder 532)
  - Wend, Emil, 1969 (Box 24, Folder 533)
  - Wesely, Josef, 1962-65 (Box 24, Folder 534)
  - Whisnant, Charleen
    See: Red Clay, Box 15, folder 378
  - Who's Who, 1930-70 (Box 24, Folder 535-36)
  - Wierzbicki, John, 1965 Jul 3 (Box 24, Folder 537)
  - Wilbur, Richard, 1971 Oct 30 (Box 24, Folder 538)
  - Williams, William Carlos, 1929-63 (Box 24, Folder 539)
  - Winslow, Ann, 1965 (Box 24, Folder 540)
  - Wolfe, Humbert, 1934 (Box 24, Folder 541)
  - Wood, Tom, 1964-65 (Box 24, Folder 542)
  - Wykes-Joyce, Max ("Oiks"), 1950, 1962 (Box 24, Folder 543)
  - Wylie, Andrew, 1968-69 (Box 24, Folder 544)
  - "Y" general, 1963-72 (Box 24, Folder 545)
  - Yale University, 1964-73 (Box 24, Folder 546)
  - Yeats, Michael, 1968-69 (Box 24, Folder 547)
  - Yeats, William Butler (calling card with note), n.d. (Box 24, Folder 548)
  - Yoder, Claire, 1971 (Box 24, Folder 549)
  - "Z" general, 1945-71 (Box 24, Folder 550)
  - Zapf (?), Elisabeth, 1965-69 (Box 24, Folder 551)
  - Zukofsky, Louis, 1928-30 (Box 24, Folder 552)
  - Drafts of letters (from Ezra Pound) (Box 25, Folder 553-59)
  - Unidentified, 1924-72, n.d. (Box 26, Folder 560-66)
  - Fan mail, 1962-69 (Box 26, Folder 567-71)
  - Fan mail, 1970-72, n.d. (Box 27, Folder 572-77)
  - Empty Envelopes, 1924-72 (Box 28, Folder 578-86)
- Writings, 1912-70; Series II; 3; (7 boxes)
  Series II, Writings, is subdivided into Books, Shorter Works, and Miscellaneous Writings, each section arranged alphabetically by title.
  - BOOKS
    - The ABC of Reading
      - Gallery proofs, 1934 Mar (Box 29, Folder 587)
      - Reviews, n.d. (Box 29, Folder 588)
    - A Lume Spento
      - Reviews (reissue), 1966 (Box 29, Folder 589)
    - Active Anthology (edited by Pound)
      - Proof sheets (incomplete), n.d. (Box 29, Folder 590)
    - L'Asse Che Non Vacilla (by Ciung Iung)
      Italian translation by Pound
      - Typescript corrected and printed text, 1945, n.d. (Box 29, Folder 591)
    - The Cantos
      - Canto I: typescript, Italian translation, corrected, n.d. (Box 29, Folder 592)
      - Canto II: typescript, Italian translation, n.d. (Box 29, Folder 593)
      - Cantos V-VII: typescript, corrected, n.d. (Box 29, Folder 594)
      - Canto VI: Italian translation, n.d. (Box 29, Folder 595)
      - Cantos XVII, XVIII, XIX: typescript, n.d. (Box 29, Folder 596)
      - Canto IX, including autographed manuscript, 1969 (Box 29, Folder 597)
      - Canto XVII: autographed manuscript, n.d. (Box 29, Folder 598)
      - Canto XXI: typescript notes, n.d. (Box 29, Folder 599)
      - Canto XXV: typescript, corrected, n.d. (Box 29, Folder 600)
      - Canto XXVI: typescript, corrected, n.d. (Box 29, Folder 601)
      - Canto XXVII, draft, n.d. (Box 29, Folder 602)
      - Canto XXVII: typescript, corrected, n.d. (Box 29, Folder 603)
      - Canto XXVIII, n.d. (Box 29, Folder 604-605)
      - Cantos XXX - LXXXIII: typescript, in French, n.d. (Box 29, Folder 606)
      - Canto XXXIII: typescript carbon, n.d. (Box 29, Folder 607)
      - Canto XLVI: typescript carbon, corrected, n.d. (Box 29, Folder 608)
      - Canto XLV: typescript carbon, corrected, n.d. (Box 29, Folder 609)
      - Canto L: typescript, corrected, n.d. (Box 29, Folder 610)
      - Canto LI, incomplete, in hand of Olga Rudge (Box 29, Folder 611)
      - Canto LIII: typescript notes, in Italian, n.d. (Box 29, Folder 612)
      - Cantos LXVIII and LXIX draft, typescript, incomplete (Box 29, Folder 613)
      - Canto LXXII: typescript draft, n.d. (Box 29, Folder 614)
      - Canto LII: typescript carbon, corrected, n.d. (Box 29, Folder 615)
      - Canto LXXII: typescript, English translation by Ezra Pound (Box 29, Folder 616)
      - Canto LXXII, n.d. (Box 29, Folder 617-619)
      - Canto LXXIII, n.d. (Box 29, Folder 620)
      - Cantos LXXII and LXXIII: typescript (Box 29, Folder 621)
      - Cantos LXXII and LXXIII: typescript, corrected, photocopy (Box 29, Folder 622)
      - Cantos LXXII and LXXIII: typescript of Italian version with Ezra Pound English translation (Box 29, Folder 623)
      - Cantos LXXIII and LXXIV: notebooks, Italian (Box 29, Folder 624)
      - Canto LXXII notes, holograph notebook, n.d. (Box 29, Folder 625)
      - Canto LXXIV: draft, n.d. (Box 29, Folder 626)
      - Cantos LXXIV - LXXXIV: typescript drafts, n.d. (Box 29, Folder 627)
      - The Pisan Cantos: manuscript excerpts, n.d. (Box 29, Folder 628)
      - Canto LXXXI: manuscript in hand of Olga Rudge (Box 29, Folder 629)
      - Canto LXXXV: note in hand of Olga Rudge (Box 29, Folder 630)
      - Canto XCIII, n.d. (Box 29, Folder 631)
      - Canto XCIX: autographed manuscript, n.d. (Box 29, Folder 632)
      - Empty folder (Box 29, Folder 633)
      - Canto C: typescript, corrected, n.d. (Box 29, Folder 634)
      - Cantos CX - CXVI: typescript drafts, corrected, n.d. (Box 29, Folder 635)
      - Cantos CX, CXI, CXII, CXIII, CXVI: typescript, corrected, n.d. (Box 29, Folder 636)
      - Cantos CX, CXII, CXIII, CXIV, CXV, CXVI: typescript photocopies, n.d. (Box 29, Folder 637)
      - Cantos CXII - CXVI: typescript drafts, n.d. (Box 30, Folder 638)
      - Cantos CX, CXVI: printed, n.d. (Box 30, Folder 639)
      - Cantos CXII, CXIV, CXV: typescript, photocopy, n.d. (Box 30, Folder 640)
      - Canto XCVII: typescript, draft, n.d. (Box 30, Folder 641)
      - "From Canto CXIII": The New Yorker, photocopy, 1968 Nov 30 (Box 30, Folder 642)
      - Canto CXIII: printed, corrected by Olga Rudge, n.d. (Box 30, Folder 643)
      - Canto CXIII: typescript, corrected, n.d. (Box 30, Folder 644)
      - Canto CXVI: typescript, corrected, n.d. (Box 30, Folder 645)
      - Canto CXV: typescript, corrected, draft, n.d. (Box 30, Folder 646)
      - Cantos CXV, CXVI: printed, with Olga Rudge's corrections, n.d. (Box 30, Folder 647)
      - Canto CXVI: autographed manuscript, n.d. (Box 30, Folder 648)
      - Canto CXX: typescript, n.d. (Box 30, Folder 649)
    - Cantos, General
      - Table of Contents for The Cantos, 1965 Sep (Box 30, Folder 650)
      - "Notes: Parts of which have been used in later drafts": page proof, 2 copies, n.d. (Box 30, Folder 651)
      - Cantos Excerpts read by Pound on Bayrische Rundfunk, in the hand of Olga Rudge (Box 30, Folder 652)
      - Notes on Cantos: autographed manuscript, n.d. (Box 30, Folder 653)
      - Notes on Cantos and Poetry Magazine: autographed manuscript (Box 30, Folder 654)
      - Notes on music in Canto LXXV, in hand of Olga Rudge (Box 30, Folder 655)
      - A Preface concerning Cantos: autographed Manuscript, in hand of Ezra Pound and Olga Rudge (Box 30, Folder 656)
      - Foreword to Selected Cantos: typescript, 1966 (Box 30, Folder 657)
      - "Foreword": autographed manuscript in the hand of Olga Rudge (Box 30, Folder 658)
      - Manuscript reading notes concerning Trojan, n.d. (Box 30, Folder 659)
      - "Analysis": typescript, corrected, n.d. (Box 30, Folder 660)
      - Miscellaneous notes and envelopes removed from Cantos manuscripts in hands of Ezra Pound, Olga Rudge, and others (Box 30, Folder 661)
      - "The Pigeons": autographed manuscript, typescript, n.d. (Box 30, Folder 662)
      - Notes on Joyce, 1963 (Box 30, Folder 663)
      - Jefferson and Mussolini: typescript draft (Box 30, Folder 664)
      - Draft of letter to Benito Mussolini: typescript carbon, 1944 Sep 29 (Box 30, Folder 665)
      - Foreword to Cavalcanti Poems: autographed manuscript by pound, autographed manuscript in hand of Olga Rudge, 1965 (Box 30, Folder 666)
      - "Cavalcanti-ballata": typescript, n.d. (Box 30, Folder 667)
      - Cavalcanti, Guido: Rime proof sheets, 1932 (Box 30, Folder 668)
      - "Alma sol Venezia", n.d. (Box 30, Folder 669)
      - Drafts for Testaments di Confucio: typescript, 1944 (Box 30, Folder 670)
      - Homage to Sextus Propertius part VIII, incomplete, autographed manuscript, n.d. (Box 30, Folder 671)
      - The Classic Anthology as defined by Confucius: passages in the hand of Olga Rudge (Box 30, Folder 672)
      - Classuc Anthology defined by Confucius: typescript, portions of books I and IV, 1950 (Box 30, Folder 673)
      - "Part of Canto XX": corrected page proof and The Exile no. 1, 1927 (Box 30, Folder 674)
      - Cantos XVII - XXVII, 1925 (Box 30, Folder 675)
      - Rock Drill promotional cards, signed by V. Scheiwiller, n.d. (Box 30, Folder 676)
      - section: Rock Drill promotional cards, n.d. (Box 30, Folder 677)
      - Hesse, Eva: Review of Drafts and Fragments, Agenda proof sheets (Box 30, Folder 678)
      - Cantos LII - LXXI: front free end paper, autographed by Pound (Box 30, Folder 679)
      - Canti Pisani: jacket, n.d. (Box 30, Folder 680)
      - Cantos of Ezra Pound: jackets (Box 30, Folder 681)
      - Review Drafts and Fragments, 1970 (Box 30, Folder 682)
      - Selected Cantos: reviews, 1969-70. n.d. (Box 30, Folder 683)
    - Classic Anthology Defined by Confucius
      - Excerpts for Spoleto readings: holograph notebook (in hand of Olga Rudge), 1970 (Box 31, Folder 684)
      - "Three Pieces for Mixed Chorus" (musical composition by Don Cobb from excerpts of Confucian odes); holograph musical score, carbon, 1967 (Box 31, Folder 685)
    - Gaudier-Brzeska: A Memoir by Ezra Pound
      - Printed text, 1916 (Box 31, Folder 686)
      - Related material, 1967, n.d. (Box 31, Folder 687)
    - A Guide to Kultur
      - Gallery proofs, n.d. (Box 31, Folder 688-91)
    - Homage to Sextus Propertius
      - Publicity, n.d. (Box 31, Folder 692)
    - "If This Be Treason"
      - Printed text, with corrections, [1948] (Box 31, Folder 693-94)
    - Instigations
      - Typescripts, corrected, and printed text (incomplete) (Box 31, Folder 695-99)
    - Kabir: Poesie (translation by Pound)
      - Page proofs, 1966 (Box 31, Folder 700)
    - Moscardino (by Enrico Pea: translation by Pound)
      - Typescript, n.d. (Box 31, Folder 701)
      - Typescript, corrected, n.d. (Box 31, Folder 702)
    - Personae
      - Gallery proofs, corrected, [1926] (Box 32, Folder 703)
      - Page proofs, [1926] (Box 32, Folder 704)
    - Selected Prose, 1909-1965
      - Foreword: holograph and typescript (Box 32, Folder 705)
    - Spots and Dots
      - Foreword and prefatory material (various drafts); holograph and typescripts (Box 32, Folder 706)
      - Notes to the text, n.d. (Box 32, Folder 707-708)
      - Publicity, n.d. (Box 32, Folder 709)
    - The Women of Trachis: A Version by Ezra Pound
      - Programs, n.d. (Box 32, Folder 710)
  - SHORTER WORKS
    - Poems
      - "A for America.. .": typescript, corrected, 1934 (Box 32, Folder 711)
      - "Au Jardin" (set to music with title "Serenade" by Viola Jenney [?]): holograph musical score, 1933 (Box 32, Folder 712)
      - "Dance Figure" (set to music by Marjorie Arden): holograph musical score with typescript of poem and accompanying letter), 1934, n.d. (Box 32, Folder 713)
      - "Glory and yet again Glory": typescript corrected, 1935 (Box 32, Folder 714)
      - "Lucidity in London.. .": typescript, corrected, 1935 (Box 32, Folder 715)
      - "Mindscapes": photocopy (Box 32, Folder 716)
      - "Near Perigord" (Polish translation by Jerzy Niemojowski). Tematy, 1965 (Box 32, Folder 717)
      - "Nicky and Frankie weren't brothers": typescript, 1934 (Box 32, Folder 718)
      - "O Weep for Buckpossum": typescript and photocopies (Box 32, Folder 719)
      - "Pacifism, 1935, as usual": typescript corrected (Box 32, Folder 720)
      - "Poems by Ezra Pound" (marked "Blast: War Number"): photocopy (Box 32, Folder 721)
      - "Privileged Communication": typescript, n.d. (Box 32, Folder 722)
      - "Provincia Deserta": typescript, n.d. (Box 32, Folder 723)
      - "Redondillas, or Something of That Sort": typescript (Box 32, Folder 724)
      - "That Radio Sex-Appeal--Ah": typescript, 1934 (Box 32, Folder 725)
      - "To Miss Stein said Miss Moore", 1937 Dec 15 (Box 32, Folder 726)
      - Limericks, n.d. (Box 32, Folder 727)
    - Musical Compositions
      - Cavalcanti
        - Notes: holograph and typescript (Box 32, Folder 728)
        - Commentaries by Pound: typescript (Box 32, Folder 729)
        - Librettos: typescript (with holograph notes), n.d. (Box 32, Folder 730)
        - Musical score (various drafts)
        - Musical score (incomplete)
      - "Fiddle Music, First Suite": holograph musical score, [c. 1924] (Box 32, Folder 731)
      - "Guidonis Sonata"
      - Hesternae Rosae: Serta II (by Walter M. Kummel. English adaptation by Pound): printed musical score, [1913] (Box 32, Folder 732)
      - "Hommage à Froissart"
      - "Monsieur Pom Pom allait en guerre": typescript (libretto), n.d. (Box 32, Folder 733)
      - "Le Testament de Villon"
        See also: Oversize, Boxes 44-45, folders 992-3
        - Holograph score, 1920-21 (Box 32, Folder 734)
        - "Emendations to Libretto of Villon": typescript, carbon (Box 32, Folder 735)
        - "Staging of the Villon": typescript, corrected, n.d. (Box 32, Folder 736)
        - Program for L'Ottovo Festivali Dei Due Mondi, 1965 (Box 32, Folder 737)
        - "The Testament of Francis Villon: A Melodrama by Ezra Pound": typescript, corrected (Box 32, Folder 738)
      - Miscellaneous musical scores: holograph notebooks, n.d. (Box 32, Folder 739-40)
      - Unidentified musical scores (uncertain authorship): holograph, n.d. (Box 32, Folder 741-42)
        See also: Oversize Box 46, folders 1012-20
    - Articles and Essays
      - "AI Communisti": typescript, n.d. (Box 33, Folder 743)
      - "Antheil: 1924-26": holograph (with printed note on "Ballet Mechanique") and typescript, corrected (Box 33, Folder 744)
      - "Anti-Fumogeno": typescript, n.d. (Box 33, Folder 745)
      - "Augment of the Novel": photocopy, n.d. (Box 33, Folder 746)
      - [The Cini Foundation]; holograph and photocopy (Box 33, Folder 747)
      - "Clandestine": typescript, corrected (Box 33, Folder 748)
      - "Cross-Words on Abomination: A Letter from Ezra Pound." The Delphian Quarterly, 1937 Jul (Box 33, Folder 749)
      - "Defini Tuoi Parola" ("Definisci Le Tue Parole"): typescript, 1940 (Box 33, Folder 750)
      - "Ecrivisse?": typescript, corrected, [1933] (Box 33, Folder 751)
      - "Editorial on Solicitous Doubt." "The Reader Critic: letters from Ezra Pound." The Little Review, [1917 Oct] (Box 33, Folder 752)
      - "For a New Paideuma"; page proofs, corrected, 1937 Nov (Box 33, Folder 753)
      - "For T. S. E. (with miscellaneous notes on Eliot): holograph, n.d. (Box 33, Folder 754)
      - "Freedom de Facto": holograph and typescript, corrected (Box 33, Folder 755)
      - "Henri Gaudier-Brzeska"
        - Holograph notes, n.d. (Box 33, Folder 756)
        - Printed text (exhibition catalogue), 1918 (Box 33, Folder 757)
      - "Historically Joyce (and Censorship)" (translation by Forrest Read): typescript, corrected, and photocopy (Box 33, Folder 758)
      - "Ideogrammario": typescript, n.d. (Box 33, Folder 759)
      - "Introductory Text Book": publicity pamphlet, n.d. (Box 33, Folder 760)
      - "Liselotte Höhs" (brief tribute): printed text, 1969 (Box 33, Folder 761)
      - "Meaning =x": gallery proofs, n.d. (Box 33, Folder 762)
      - "Money"; typescript, corrected, 1935 (Box 33, Folder 763)
      - "Notes for Broletti Article": typescript, corrected, n.d. (Box 33, Folder 764)
      - "Notes" to Harry Crosby, Torchbearer: page proofs, corrected, [1931] (Box 33, Folder 765)
      - "Olga Rudge": typescript, 1927 (Box 33, Folder 766)
      - "Olga Rudge: nei studi Vivaldiani": typescript, n.d. (Box 33, Folder 767)
      - "Oro E. Lavora"
        - Typescript ("La Moda Dell' Utopia"), n.d. (Box 33, Folder 768)
        - Printed text, 1944 (Box 33, Folder 769)
      - "Patriotismo": typescript, corrected, and carbon (Box 33, Folder 770)
      - "Peace, Perfect and Unburler'd" [sic], 1941 (Box 33, Folder 771)